

Soohwan KIM

Profile

Current co-founder and AI Research Engineer of TUNiB Inc. My research interests include technologies for human-machine interaction, such as automatic speech recognition, speech synthesis, and natural language processing. I want to be helpful to others through open source.

Education

Kwangwoon University

March 2014 — February 2021

- Major in Electronic & Communication Engineering
- · Minor in Data Science.
- Major GPA: 3.90 / 4.5, Total GPA: 3.68 / 4.5

Employment History

TUNIB Inc.

March 2021 — Present

- · Co-founder & AI Research Engineer
- Startup based on natural language processing technology.
- · Website: www.tunib.ai

Kakao Brain Corp.

November 2020 — February 2021

- Al Research Engineer (Speech & NLP TEAM)
- Developed a natural language processing library named pororo
- · Website: www.kakaobrain.com

Internships

Kakao Brain Corp.

August 2020 — November 2020

- Al Research Internship (Speech & NLP TEAM)
- Developed speech recognition & speech synthesis technologies.

Spoken Language Lab (of Sogang Univ.)

April 2020 — August 2020

- Research Internship
- Studies speech recognition task based on deep learning.
- Website: http://speech.sogang.ac.kr/

Publication

Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition Soohwan Kim, Seyoung Bae, Cheolhwang Won (ELSEVIER, SIMPAC)

E2E Speech Recognition Models in English, Chinese, and Korean Soohwan Kim (Bachelor's Graduation Thesis)

Details

1206-5 Bojeong-dong, Giheung-gu Yongin-si, Gyeonggi-do Seoul, 16898 South Korea +82-10-4564-4668 kaki.ai@tunib.ai

Date / Place of birth 1995.10.11 Cheonan-si

Links

GitHub Tech Blog (GitHub) Tech Blog (Naver) Linkedin Facebook

SkillsPython

PyTorch
Fairseq
Numpy
Git
Java
C
Shell Script

Pandas
Faiss
Hydra
SQL
Android

Assembly

HTML

Project Experience

PORORO: Platform Of neuRal mOdels for natuRal language prOcessing, Kakao Brain

November 2020 — February 2021

- Performs natural language processing and speech-related tasks.
- Easy to solve various subtasks in the nlp & speech field.
- GitHub: https://github.com/kakaobrain/pororo

Multilingual Text-To-Speech, Kakao Brain

October 2020 — February 2021

- · Supports 11 languages.
- Supports voice style transfer, and code-switching functions.
- Demo page: https://pororo-tts.github.io/

English, Chinese, and Korean End-to-End Automatic Speech Recognition, Kakao Brain

August 2020 — October 2020

- Develop and compare models (LAS, Transformer, Wav2vec 2.0)
- Performance and speed comparison by output unit.

KoSpeech: Open-Source Toolkit for End-to-End Korean Speech Recognition, Spoken Language Lab

January 2020 — Present

- Extensible end-to-end Korean speech recognition toolkit.
- Most popular Korean speech recognition project in GitHub.
- GitHub: https://github.com/sooftware/KoSpeech

Extra-curricular activities

Speech Paper Reading

December 2020 — Present

- Weekly meeting where people who work in the field of Speech.
- Read the paper and share each opinions.
- https://github.com/speech-paper-reading/speech-paper-reading

NLP Paper Reading

September 2020 — February 2021

- Kakao Brain NLP Team's weekly paper reading study.
- Read the paper and share each opinions.
- https://github.com/kakaobrain/nlp-paper-reading

Teaching Experience

SAMSUNG AI Expert Course

July 2020 — August 2020

• Conduct teaching assistant role in the speech recognition session.

Object-Oriented Programming Practice Lecture

March 2020 — June 2020

- Covered basic java programming,
- Ran laboratories and had office hours every week.
- Answered students questions in person and marked assignments.